ASHWIN SINGH

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- **Q** 647-823-8722
- 🔼 Ashwin.Singh.087@gmail.com
- AshwinSingh.dev
- /in/AshwinSingh087

PROFILE

I am a detail-oriented Front-End Developer with a passion for building practical and efficient apps. My previous experience as a policy analyst and material planner allows me to take a design and build a program from the ground up, down to the last detail. My curiosity for solving problems and learning fuels my drive to write clear and concise code.

EDUCATION

JUNO COLLEGE

OCT 2020 - JULY 2021

- Immersive Bootcamp
- Web Development & JavaScript

SENECA COLLEGE

JAN 2017 - DEC 2017

• Government Relations

YORK UNIVERSITY

SEPT 2011 - JUNE 2015

• Kinesiology and Health Science

SKILLS







JavaScript







React

Firebase



Rest API's

JQuery

PROJECTS

NOTBLOCKBUSTER 🗹 😱



React | Firebase | Rest API | CSS 3 | Mob Programmed Movie app built using React Router where users can explore and save movies to a filterable list connected to Firebase.

DAILY CRYPTO UPDATE 🗹 😱





ES6 JavaScript | SASS | Rest API | Pair Programmed Searchable cryptocurrency app, the highlighting feature is an accessible auto-suggest search bar users can select from.

ARTIST DISCOGRAPHY [7]



React | Firebase | Rest API | HTML 5 | CSS 3 Music app which allows users to find an artist's discography and save their favorite albums to a list stored on Firebase.

EXPERIENCE

WORK MATERIAL PLANNER

Bombardier Aerospace | Feb 2019 - June 2020

- Worked cross-functionally with other departments including engineering and production to resolve issues that would prevent the team from fulfilling their deliverables within the 5-day work flow.
- Managed station's work flow to ensure timely delivery of priorities and commitments including electronic material management using SAP and proactively procuring required materials.
- Managed logistic inquiries by addressing and resolving issues that occurred, advising other departments about proper procedures and correct next steps, and expediting urgent deliverables.

JUNIOR POLICY ANALYST

Ontario Public Service | Sept 2017 - Dec 2017

- Led the development of a joint ministry pilot project which included determining the approach, structuring the program, drafting all necessary documents, and facilitating the approval process with senior management.
- Liaised with other divisions and ministry partners to coordinate program development and implementation, provide opportunities for engagement and updates about recent developments on key files.